Curriculum Vitae

Ibrahim O. Shanqiti

Tel No. +971 55 1913121

Email: <u>ibrahim.shanqiti@gmail.com</u> - <u>ibrahimshanqiti@diaestudents.com</u>

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Ibrahimshanqiti.com

Education-Focused Channel

Summary:

All Rounded Student at Dubai International Academy in 11C. Bilingual in Arabic and English. Highly focused and proficient in Physics, Mathematics and English literature and History, and a strong negotiator and debater. I am fluent in different Adobe products, such as Photoshop and After Effects, I am a passionate writer and author as seen in my involvement in the school club DIALect. I also try to keep myself active in different extracurriculars around school. I am also competent in most technologies, with experience with PC building, and my education based youtube channel, linked above. I try to balance the tech-based lifestyle by participating in as many sporting activities as I can, including hiking, long-distance cycling, and swimming. I beekeep from time to time as a hobby. I have strong teamwork and leadership skills, and great collaborative skills.

Academic History:

- **2008-2011** - KG 2 - Year 3

Al Mawakeb - Barsha:

California NGSS, California CCSSM, California CCSSE

- **2012 - 2018** - Year 4 - Year 11

Dubai International Academy - Emirates Hills:

IB Curriculum

Certifications:

- OPR Suicide Prevention Certified
- Deputy Heart Attack Course Certified
- PFA (Psychological First Aid) Course from NCTSN Certified
- FEMA Safety Travel Rules & Regulations Certified
- FEMA Active Shooter: What can you do Certified.

Experience:

Model United Nations:

- 5 Years experience of the After School Activity (Have assisted teaching)
- 2015 DIAMUN Conference Delegate
- 2018-2019 EISJ Conference (Best Delegate Award) Delegate
- 2018-2019 DIAMUN Conference (Best Delegate Award) Delegate
- 2019-2020 EISJ Conference (Best Delegate Award Security Council) Delegate
- 2020 DIAMUN Conference Chair (Conference cancelled, chair training only)

Student Bodies:

- 1 Year as Student Council (2018-2019)
- 1 Year Deputy House Captain (House Air) (2019-2020)
- 1 Year Friendship Ambassador (2019-2020)

Online Courses:

- Introduction to Philosophy University of Edinburgh (2020)
- Precalculus Arizona State University
- Leading Teams University of Michigan (Audited)

DIALect:

- Deputy Writer for the Mini-Howler (2018-2019)
- Head Writer for the News Society (International News) (2019-2020)

Water for Life:

- Deputy Head of Media and Communications (2019-2020)

Duke of Edinburgh Award:

- Bronze Award (in development, Camping Trip has been passed)
- 2018 2019 Duke of Edinburgh Student Officer
- Silver Award (in development, Camping Trip has been passed)

Skills:

- Technology: PC Building, Mac, Windows, hardware.
- Languages: English (fluent speaking and writing), Arabic (fluent speaking).
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Graphic Design: Photoshop, Illustrator (basic)
- Video Editing: After Effects, Sony Vegas Pro, and Adobe Premiere Pro (basic).
- Instruments: Piano Grade 5 ABRSM, Beginner Ukulele,
- Intermediate Programming skills Python 3, HTML, CSS.

Soft Skills:

- Excellent teamwork skills.
- Very strong public speaking skills.
- Excellent Debating skills.
- Good communication skills Listening and speaking.
- Works very well under pressure.
- Strong Proficiency in video & image editing.
- Skilled in creative & journalistic writing.
- Great helper to others and works well with other people.
- Adapts to foreign situations well.
- Superb leading skills.